<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
<meta name="date" content="2015-09-07T18:00:19Z"/>
<meta name="pdf:PDFVersion" content="1.5"/>
<meta name="xmp:CreatorTool" content="LaTeX with hyperref package"/>
<meta name="Keywords" content="Amir AghaKouchak, CV, civil, environmental, water resources"/>
<meta name="access_permission:modify_annotations" content="true"/>
<meta name="access_permission:can_print_degraded" content="true"/>
<meta name="subject" content="Curriculum Vitae"/>
<meta name="dcterms:created" content="2015-09-07T18:00:19Z"/>
<meta name="Last-Modified" content="2015-09-07T18:00:19Z"/>
<meta name="dcterms:modified" content="2015-09-07T18:00:19Z"/>
<meta name="dc:format" content="application/pdf; version=1.5"/>
<meta name="Last-Save-Date" content="2015-09-07T18:00:19Z"/>
<meta name="access_permission:fill_in_form" content="true"/>
<meta name="meta:save-date" content="2015-09-07T18:00:19Z"/>
<meta name="pdf:encrypted" content="false"/>
<meta name="dc:title" content="Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE: Curriculum Vitae"/>
<meta name="modified" content="2015-09-07T18:00:19Z"/>
<meta name="cp:subject" content="Curriculum Vitae"/>
<meta name="Content-Length" content="169594"/>
<meta name="Content-Type" content="application/pdf"/>
<meta name="PTEX.Fullbanner" content="This is MiKTeX-pdfTeX 2.9.4198 (1.40.12)"/>
<meta name="X-Parsed-By" content="org.apache.tika.parser.DefaultParser"/>
<meta name="X-Parsed-By" content="org.apache.tika.parser.pdf.PDFParser"/>
<meta name="dc:subject" content="Amir AghaKouchak, CV, civil, environmental, water resources"/>
<meta name="trapped" content="False"/>
<meta name="meta:creation-date" content="2015-09-07T18:00:19Z"/>
<meta name="created" content="Mon Sep 07 11:00:19 PDT 2015"/>
<meta name="access_permission:extract_for_accessibility" content="true"/>
<meta name="access_permission:assemble_document" content="true"/>
<meta name="xmpTPg:NPages" content="25"/>
<meta name="Creation-Date" content="2015-09-07T18:00:19Z"/>
<meta name="resourceName" content="cv_amir.pdf"/>
<meta name="access_permission:extract_content" content="true"/>
<meta name="access_permission:can_print" content="true"/>
<meta name="meta:keyword" content="Amir AghaKouchak, CV, civil, environmental, water resources"/>
<meta name="producer" content="pdfTeX-1.40.12"/>
<meta name="access_permission:can_modify" content="true"/>
<title>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE: Curriculum Vitae</title>
</head>
<body><div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE
Amir AghaKouchak
Dept. of Civil &amp; Environmental Engineer-
ing
University of California Irvine
E/4130 Engineering Gateway
Irvine, CA 92697
</p>
<p>Office: (949) 824-9350
Mobile: (949) 231-8987
Fax: (949) 824-8831
Email: amir.a@uci.edu
Website: http://amir.eng.uci.edu/
</p>
<p>Amir
</p>
<p>Current Position
</p>
<p>Assistant Professor, University of California, Irvine
</p>
<p>Professional Licensure
</p>
<p>Professional Licensed Civil Engineer in the State of California (License Number: 78586).
</p>
<p>Education
</p>
<p>PhD, Civil and Environmental Engineering, University of Stuttgart, Germany, 2010
</p>
<p>Dissertation: Simulation of remotely sensed rainfall fields using copulas
</p>
<p>MSc, Civil Engineering - Water Resources, K.N.Toosi University of Technology, Tehran, Iran,
2005
</p>
<p>BSc, Civil Engineering (Major: Water Resources), K.N.Toosi University of Technology,
Tehran, Iran, 2003
</p>
<p>Academic Experience
</p>
<p>Assistant Professor, University of California, Irvine, Irvine, CA, Jul. 2011 - present.
</p>
<p>Postdoctoral Associate, University of California, Irvine, Irvine, CA, Jan. 2010 - Jun. 2011.
</p>
<p>Visiting Scholar, University of Louisiana at Lafayette, Lafayette, LA, Dec. 2007 - Oct. 2009.
</p>
<p>Graduate Student, University of Stuttgart, Stuttgart, Germany, Oct. 2005 - Nov. 2009.
</p>
<p>Honors &amp; Awards
</p>
<p>2014 United States Frontiers of Engineering (FOE), National Academy of Engineering
(NAE) of the National Academies ("The FOE program brings together a select group of emerg-
ing engineering leaders from industry, academe, and government labs to discuss pioneering
technical work and leading edge research in various engineering fields and industry sectors").</p>
<p/>
<div class="annotation"><a href="http://amir.eng.uci.edu/"/></div>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 2
</p>
<p>2014-15 Early Career Innovation in Teaching Award.
</p>
<p>2013-14 Hellman Fellowship Award.
</p>
<p>2012 Frontiers of Engineering Education (FOEE) Award, National Academy of Engineer-
ing (NAE) of the National Academies ("The FOEE program brings together some of the na-
tion’s most engaged and innovative engineering educators in order to recognize, reward, and
promote effective, substantive, and inspirational engineering education through a sustained
dialogue within the emerging generation of innovative faculty").
</p>
<p>World Climate Research Programme (WCRP) award to support participation and oral pre-
sentation in the WCRP Workshop on Drought Predictability and Prediction in a Changing
Climate, March 2-4, 2011, Barcelona, Spain.
</p>
<p>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Educational Partnership Pro-
gram Award, 2009.
</p>
<p>Grants, Awards &amp; Projects
</p>
<p>Total funding: PI: $2,187,049; Co-PI/Co-I: $9,328,172
</p>
<p>14. Title: Advancing Drought Onset Detection and Seasonal Prediction Using a Composite
of NASA Models and Satellite Data Agency: NASA; Dates: 12/1/14-11/30/18
Funding: $1,172,549; PI: Amir AghaKouchak
</p>
<p>13. Title: A Nested Multi-Scale Hydrological Modeling Framework: Assessing Resilience and
Vulnerability to Climate Change
Agency: NSF-Hydrological Sciences; Dates: 9/1/13-8/31/16
Funding: $225,000; PI: Amir AghaKouchak
</p>
<p>12. Title: Advancing Drought Monitoring and Prediction Using a Multi-Index Multivariate
Framework
Agency: NOAA; Dates: 9/1/14-8/31/17
Funding: $440,000 (UCI’s share: $247,000); Lead PI: Amir AghaKouchak; Co-PIs:
Andy Wood, Mark Svoboda
</p>
<p>11. Title: Drought Emergency Seasonal Forecasting via Conditional Analog Year
Agency: CA Dept. of Water Resources; Dates: 10/1/14-5/31/15
Funding: $134,599; PI: Amir AghaKouchak
</p>
<p>10. Title: Frameworks for Analysis of Regional, Concurrent, Conditional and Non-Stationary
Extremes in Geosciences
Agency: ARL; Dates: 12/1/14-8/31/15
Funding: $50,000; PI: Amir AghaKouchak
</p>
<p>9. Title: Drought Monitoring Using NASA Atmospheric Infrared Sounder (AIRS) Data
Agency: NASA; Dates: 10/1/14-9/30/15
Funding: $54,000; PI: Amir AghaKouchak</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 3
</p>
<p>8. Title: Global Integrated Drought Monitoring and Prediction System
Agency: NSF - Innovation Corps (I-Corps); Dates: 10/1/13-9/30/14
Funding: $50,000; PI: Amir AghaKouchak
</p>
<p>7. Title: Building a Climate Change Resilient Electricity System for Meeting California’s
Energy and Environmental Goals
Agency: California Energy Commission (CEC); Dates: 07/1/15-6/30/18
Funding: $698,792; PI: Scott Samuelsen; Co-Investigators: Amir AghaKouchak, Brian
Tarroja, David Feldman, Brendan P. Shaffer, Kaveh Madani
</p>
<p>6. Title: Hazards SEES Type 2: Preventing Flood Hazards from Becoming Disasters through
Two-Way Communication of Parcel-Level Flood Risk
Agency: NSF; Dates: 09/1/14-8/31/17
Funding: $2,819,380; PI: Brett Sanders; Investigators: Amir AghaKouchak, Victoria
Basolo, John Houston, Richard Matthew, James Famiglietti
</p>
<p>5. Title: Low Energy Options for Making Water from Wastewater
Agency: NSF; Dates: 10/1/12-9/30/17
Funding: $4,900,000; PI: Stanley Grant; Investigators: Amir AghaKouchak, R Ambrose,
P Bowler, B Cooper, R Detwiler, S Elghobashi, D Feldman, S Jiang, R Lejano, L Levin, M
McBride, M Prather, J.D. Saphores, D Rosso, B Sanders, A Sengupta, E Stein, M Sutula,
W Tang, K Treseder, J Vrugt, R Brown, P Cook, A Deletic, T Fletcher, A Hamilton, I
Marusic, D McCarthy, M Stewardson, A Western
</p>
<p>4. Title: Analysis of Weather and Climate Extremes Using AIRS Satellite Data
Agency: NASA; Dates: 5/1/13-4/30/14
Funding: $53,901; PI: Amir AghaKouchak
</p>
<p>3. Title: Quantifying Climate Projections Uncertainty Using a Non-Gaussian Model and an
Adaptive Weighting Ensemble Algorithm: Application to Water Resources Management
Agency: USBR; Dates: 9/1/11-8/31/13
Funding: $200,000; PI: Amir AghaKouchak; Co-PI: Jialun Li
</p>
<p>2. Title: Improving near real-time high-resolution satellite-derived precipitation estimation
for hydrologic modeling and decision-making applications
Agency: ARL; Dates: 10/1/11-9/30/13
Funding: $670,000; PI: Soroosh Sorooshian; Co-PIs: Amir AghaKouchak, Kuolin Hsu,
Xiaogang Gao
</p>
<p>1. Title: Impacts of Global Climate Change (GCC) on the Water Resources of Morocco
Agency: World Bank; Dates: 8/1/11-12/31/12
Funding: $240,000; PI: Soroosh Sorooshian; Co-PIs: Amir AghaKouchak, Jialun Li
</p>
<p>Editorial
</p>
<p>Editorial Board Member, Scientific Reports (Nature Publishing Group), 2015-present.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 4
</p>
<p>Editorial Board Member, Scientific Data (Nature Publishing Group), 2014-present.
</p>
<p>Editor, Extremes in a Changing Climate: Detection, Analysis &amp; Uncertainty, 2013, Springer.
</p>
<p>Reviewer, Water Resources Research (AGU), Geophysical Research Letters (AGU), Journal
of Hydrometeorology (AMS), Journal of Geophysical Research (AGU), Journal of Climate
(AMS), Theoretical and Applied Climatology (Springer), Hydrology and Earth System Sci-
ences (EGU), Advances in Water Resources (Elsevier), Journal of Hydrology (Elsevier), En-
vironmental Modelling and Software (Elsevier), Atmospheric Research (Elsevier), Stochas-
tic Environmental Research and Risk Assessment (Springer), Computer Applications in
Engineering Education (Wiley), Journal of Applied Meteorology and Climatology (AMS),
Journal of Hydrologic Engineering (ASCE), Hydrological Sciences Journal (IAHS), Journal
of Water Resources Planning and Management (ASCE), Regional Environmental Change
(Springer), Natural Hazards and Earth System Sciences (EGU), Computers &amp; Geosciences
(Elsevier), Journal of the American Water Resources Association (Wiley), Water Resources
Management (Springer), Remote Sensing (MDPI), Water (MDPI), Water Science and Tech-
nology (IWA).
</p>
<p>Patent
</p>
<p>Global Integrated Drought Monitoring and Prediction System (GIDMaPS), United States
Pending Patent (EFS ID: 15781319, Application Number: 61823491), AghaKouchak A.,
Hao Z., Nakhjiri N., 2013.
Selected as a 2013 National Science Foundation (NSF) Innovation Corps (I-Corps).
</p>
<p>Publications
</p>
<p>Journal Publications (Students and Postdocs Underlined)
</p>
<p>58. AghaKouchak A., Feldman D., Hoerling M., Huxman T., Lund J., 2015, Recognize An-
thropogenic Drought, Nature, 524 (7566), 409-4011, doi:10.1038/524409a.
</p>
<p>57. Mazdiyasni O., AghaKouchak A., 2015, Substantial Increase in Concurrent Droughts
and Heatwaves in the United States, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences,
doi: 10.1073/pnas.1422945112.
</p>
<p>56. Vahedifard F., AghaKouchak A., Robinson J.D., 2015, Drought threatens California’s
levees, Science, 349 (6250), 799, doi: 10.1126/science.349.6250.799-a.
</p>
<p>55. AghaKouchak A., Farahmand A., Teixeira J., Wardlow B.D., Melton F.S., Anderson M.C.,
Hain C.R., 2015, Remote Sensing of Drought: Progress, Challenges and Opportunities,
Reviews of Geophysics, 53(2), 452-480, doi: 10.1002/2014RG000456.
</p>
<p>54. Mehran A., Mazdiyasni O., AghaKouchak A., 2015, A Hybrid Framework for Assess-
ing Socioeconomic Drought: Linking Climate Variability, Local Resilience, and Demand,
Journal of Geophysical Research, 120 (15), 7520–7533, doi: 10.1002/2015JD023147.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 5
</p>
<p>53. Shukla S., Safeeq M., AghaKouchak A., Guan K., Funk C., 2015, Temperature Impacts
on the Water Year 2014 Drought in California, Geophysical Research Letters, 42, 4384-
4393, doi: 10.1002/2015GL063666.
</p>
<p>52. Askarizadeh A., Rippy M., Fletcher T., Feldman D., Peng J., Bowler P., Mehring A., Win-
frey B., Vrugt J., AghaKouchak A., Jiang S., Sanders B., Levin L., Taylor S., Grant S.,
2015, From rain tanks to catchments: Use of low-impact development to address hydro-
logic symptoms of the urban stream syndrome, Environmental Science &amp; Technology,
doi: 10.1021/acs.est.5b01635.
</p>
<p>51. AghaKouchak A., Norouzi H., Madani K., Mirchi A., Azarderakhsh M., Nazemi N., Nas-
rollahi N., Mehran M., Farahmand A., Hasanzadeh E., 2015, Aral Sea Syndrome Desic-
cates Lake Urmia: Call for Action, Journal of Great Lakes Research, 41(1), 307-311,
doi: 10.1016/j.jglr.2014.12.007.
</p>
<p>50. Cheng L., AghaKouchak A., Phillips T., 2015, Non-stationary Return Levels of CMIP5
Multi-Model Temperature Extremes, Climate Dynamics, 44(11), 2947-2963, doi:
10.1007/s00382-015-2625-y.
</p>
<p>49. Nasrollahi N., AghaKouchak A., Cheng L., Damberg L., Phillips T., Miao C., Hsu K.,
Sorooshian S., 2015, How Well Do CMIP5 Climate Simulations Replicate Historical
Trends and Patterns of Meteorological Droughts?, Water Resources Research, 51(4),
2847-2864, doi: 10.1002/2014WR016318.
</p>
<p>48. Cheng L., AghaKouchak A., 2015, A Methodology for Deriving Ensemble Re-
sponse from Multimodel Simulations, Journal of Hydrology, 522, 49-57, doi:
10.1016/j.jhydrol.2014.12.025.
</p>
<p>47. Farahmand A., AghaKouchak A., Teixeira J., 2015, A Vantage from Space Can Detect
Earlier Drought Onset: An Approach Using Relative Humidity, Scientific Reports, 5,
8553, doi: 10.1038/srep08553.
</p>
<p>46. AghaKouchak A., 2015, A Multivariate Approach for Persistence-Based Drought Predic-
tion: Application to the 2010-2011 East Africa Drought, Journal of Hydrology, 526,
127-135, doi: 10.1016/j.jhydrol.2014.09.063.
</p>
<p>45. Farahmand A., AghaKouchak A., 2015, A Generalized Framework for Deriving Nonpara-
metric Standardized Drought Indicators, Advances in Water Resources, 76, 140-145,
doi: 10.1016/j.advwatres.2014.11.012.
</p>
<p>44. Prakash S., Mitra A.K., AghaKouchak A., Pai D.S., 2015, Error characterization of TRMM
Multisatellite Precipitation Analysis (TMPA-3B42) products over India for different sea-
sons, Journal of Hydrology, doi: 10.1016/j.jhydrol.2015.08.062.
</p>
<p>43. Nguyen P., Thorstensen A., Sorooshian S., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., 2015, Flood Fore-
casting and Inundation Mapping Using Hiresflood-Uci and Near Real-Time Satellite Pre-
cipitation Data: The 2008 Iowa Flood, Journal of Hydrometeorology, 16(3), 1171-
1183, doi: 10.1175/JHM-D-14-0212.1.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 6
</p>
<p>42. Norouzi H., Temimi M., AghaKouchak A., Azarderakhsh M., Khanbilvardi R., Shields
G., Tesfagiorgis K., 2015, Inferring Land Surface Parameters from the Diurnal Variability
of Microwave and Infrared Temperatures, Physics and Chemistry of the Earth, doi:
10.1016/j.pce.2015.01.007.
</p>
<p>41. Golian S., Mazdiyasni O., AghaKouchak A., 2015, Trends in Meteorological and Agri-
cultural Droughts in Iran, Theoretical and Applied Climatology, 119, 679-688, doi:
10.1007/s00704-014-1139-6.
</p>
<p>40. Li J., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., Sorooshian S., 2015, An Object-based Approach for Ver-
ification of Precipitation Estimation, International Journal of Remote Sensing, 36(2),
513-529, doi: 10.1080/01431161.2014.999170.
</p>
<p>39. AghaKouchak A., Cheng L., Mazdiyasni O., Farahmand A., 2014, Global Warming
and Changes in Risk of Concurrent Climate Extremes: Insights from the 2014
California Drought, Geophysical Research Letters, 41 (24), 8847-8852, doi:
10.1002/2014GL062308.
</p>
<p>38. AghaKouchak A., Feldman D., Stewardson M.J., Saphores J.-D., Grant S., Sanders B.,
2014, Australia’s Drought: Lessons for California, Science, 343 (6178), 1430-1431,
doi:10.1126/science.343.6178.1430.
</p>
<p>37. Cheng L., AghaKouchak A., 2014, Nonstationary Precipitation Intensity-Duration-
Frequency Curves for Infrastructure Design in a Changing Climate, Scientific Reports,
4, 7093, doi:10.1038/srep07093.
</p>
<p>36. AghaKouchak A., 2014, Entropy-Copula in Hydrology and Climatology, Journal of Hy-
drometeorology, 15(6), 2176-2189, doi: 10.1175/JHM-D-13-0207.1.
</p>
<p>35. Cheng L., AghaKouchak A., Gilleland E., Katz R.W., 2014, Non-stationary Extreme
Value Analysis in a Changing Climate, Climatic Change, 127(2), 353-369, doi:
10.1007/s10584-014-1254-5.
</p>
<p>34. Hao Z., AghaKouchak A., Farahmand A., Nakhjiri N., 2014, Global Integrated
Drought Monitoring and Prediction System, Scientific Data, 1:140001, doi:
10.1038/sdata.2014.1.
</p>
<p>33. Cheng L., Gilleland E., Heaton M.J., AghaKouchak A., 2014, Empirical Bayes estimation
for the conditional extreme value model, Stat, 3, 391-406, doi: 10.1002/sta4.71.
</p>
<p>32. Mehran A., AghaKouchak A., Phillips T.J., 2014, Evaluation of CMIP5 Continental Pre-
cipitation Simulations Relative to Satellite-Based Gauge-Adjusted Observations, Journal
of Geophysical Research, 119(4), 1695-1707, doi: 10.1002/2013JD021152.
</p>
<p>31. Song X., Zhang J., AghaKouchak A., Sen Roy S., Xuan Y., Wang G., He R., Wang X., Liu
C., 2014, Rapid Urbanization and Changes in Spatiotemporal Characteristics of Precipi-
tation in Beijing Metropolitan Area, Journal of Geophysical Research, 119(19), 11250-
11271, doi: 10.1002/2014JD022084.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 7
</p>
<p>30. Sorooshian S., AghaKouchak A., Li J., 2014, Influence of Irrigation on Land Hydrologi-
cal Processes over California, Journal of Geophysical Research, 119 (23), 13137-13152,
doi: 10.1002/2014JD022232.
</p>
<p>29. Tabari H., AghaKouchak A., Willems P., 2014, A Perturbation Approach for Assessing
Trends in Precipitation Extremes across Iran, Journal of Hydrology, 519, 1420-1427,
doi: 10.1016/j.jhydrol.2014.09.019.
</p>
<p>28. Tarroja B., AghaKouchak A., Samuelsen S., Sobhani R., Feldman D., Jiang S.,
2014, Evaluating Options for Balancing the Water-Electricity Nexus in Califor-
nia: Part 1 - Securing Water Availability, Science of the Total Environment, doi:
10.1016/j.scitotenv.2014.06.060.
</p>
<p>27. Tarroja B., AghaKouchak A., Samuelsen S., Sobhani R., Feldman D., Jiang S., 2014,
Evaluating Options for Balancing the Water-Electricity Nexus in California: Part 2 -
Greenhouse Gas and Renewable Energy Utilization Impacts, Science of the Total En-
vironment, doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2014.06.071.
</p>
<p>26. AghaKouchak A., 2014, A Baseline Probabilistic Drought Forecasting Framework Using
Standardized Soil Moisture Index: Application to the 2012 United States Drought, Hy-
drology and Earth System Sciences, 18, 2485-2492, doi: 10.5194/hess-18-2485-2014.
</p>
<p>25. Momtaz F., Nakhjiri N., AghaKouchak A., 2014, Toward a Drought Cyberinfrastructure
System, Eos, Transactions American Geophysical Union, 95 (22), 182-183.
</p>
<p>24. Hao Z., AghaKouchak A., 2014, A Nonparametric Multivariate Multi-Index Drought
Monitoring Framework, Journal of Hydrometeorology, 15, 89-101, doi:10.1175/JHM-
D-12-0160.1.
</p>
<p>23. Liu Z., Mehran A., Phillips T., AghaKouchak A., 2014, Seasonal and Regional Biases in
CMIP5 Precipitation Simulations, Climate Research, 60, 35-50, doi: 10.3354/cr01221.
</p>
<p>22. Mehran A., AghaKouchak A., 2014, Capabilities of Satellite Precipitation datasets to
Estimate Heavy Precipitation Rates at Different Temporal Accumulations, Hydrological
Processes, 28, 2262-2270, doi: 10.1002/ hyp.9779.
</p>
<p>21. Damberg L., AghaKouchak A., 2014, Global Trends and Patterns of Droughts from
Space, Theoretical and Applied Climatology, 117(3) 441-448, doi: 10.1007/s00704-
013-1019-5.
</p>
<p>20. AghaKouchak A., Mehran A., 2013, Extended Contingency Table: Performance Metrics
for Satellite Observations and Climate Model Simulations, Water Resources Research,
49, 7144-7149, doi:10.1002/wrcr.20498.
</p>
<p>19. Hao Z., AghaKouchak A., Phillips T.J., 2013, Changes in Concurrent Monthly Precip-
itation and Temperature Extremes, Environmental Research Letters, 8(4), 034014,
doi:10.1088/1748-9326/8/3/034014.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 8
</p>
<p>18. Farahmand A., AghaKouchak A., 2013, A Satellite-Based Global Landslide Model, Nat-
ural Hazards and Earth System Sciences, 13, 1259-1267, doi:10.5194/nhess-13-1259-
2013.
</p>
<p>17. Hao Z., AghaKouchak A., 2013, Multivariate Standardized Drought Index: A
Parametric Multi-Index Model, Advances in Water Resources, 57, 12-18, doi:
10.1016/j.advwatres.2013.03.009.
</p>
<p>16. AghaKouchak A., Nakhjiri N., and Habib E., 2013, An educational model for ensemble
streamflow simulation and uncertainty analysis, Hydrology and Earth System Sciences,
17, 445-452, doi:10.5194/hess-17-445-2013.
</p>
<p>15. AghaKouchak A., Nakhjiri N., 2012, A Near Real-Time Satellite-Based Global
Drought Climate Data Record, Environmental Research Letters, 7 (4), 044037,
doi:10.1088/1748-9326/7/4/044037.
</p>
<p>14. AghaKouchak A., Mehran A., Norouzi H., Behrangi A., 2012, Systematic and Random
Error Components in Satellite Precipitation Data Sets, Geophysical Research Letters, 39,
L09406, doi:10.1029/2012GL051592.
</p>
<p>13. Nasrollahi N., AghaKouchak A., Li J., Gao X., Hsu K., Sorooshian S., 2012, Assessing
the impacts of different WRF parameterization schemes in hurricane modeling, Weather
and Forecasting, 27 (4), 1003-1016, doi:10.1175/WAF-D-10-05000.1.
</p>
<p>12. Sorooshian S., AghaKouchak A., Arkin P., Eylander J., Foufoula-Georgiou E., Harmon R.,
Hendrickx J., Imam B., Kuligowski R., Skahill B., Skofronick-Jackson G., 2011, Advanced
Concepts on Remote Sensing of Precipitation at Multiple Scales, Bulletin of the Ameri-
can Meteorological Society, 92 (10), 1353-1357, doi: 10.1175/2011BAMS3158.1.
</p>
<p>11. AghaKouchak A., Behrangi A., Sorooshian S., Hsu K., Amitai E., 2011, Validation of
satellite-retrieved extreme precipitation Rates across the Central United States, Journal
of Geophysical Research, 116, D02115, doi: 10.1029/2010JD014741.
</p>
<p>10. AghaKouchak A., Nasrollahi N., Li J., Imam B., Sorooshian S., 2011, Geometrical Char-
acterization of Precipitation Patterns, Journal of Hydrometeorology, 12 (2), 274-285,
doi: 10.1175/2010JHM1298.
</p>
<p>9. Behrangi A., Khakbaz B., Jaw T.C., AghaKouchak A., Hsu K., Sorooshian S., 2011, Hy-
drologic Evaluation of Satellite Precipitation Products over a Mid-size Basin, 397, 225-
237, Journal of Hydrology, doi: 10.1016/j.jhydrol.2010.11.043.
</p>
<p>8. AghaKouchak A., Bárdossy A., Habib E., 2010, Conditional Simulation of Remotely
Sensed Rainfall Fields Using a Non-Gaussian V-Transformed Copula, Advances in Water
resources, 33 (6), 624-634,
doi:10.1016/j.advwatres.2010.02.010.
</p>
<p>7. AghaKouchak A., Bárdossy A., Habib E., 2010, Copula-based uncertainty modeling:
Application to multi-sensor precipitation estimates, Hydrological Processes, 24 (15),
2111-2124, doi: 10.1002/hyp.7632.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 9
</p>
<p>6. AghaKouchak A., Habib E., Bárdossy A., 2010, Modeling Radar Rainfall Estimation
Uncertainties: Random Error Model, Journal of Hydrologic Engineering, 15(4), 265-
274, doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)HE.1943-5584.0000185.
</p>
<p>5. AghaKouchak A., Nasrollahi, N., 2010, Semi-parametric and parametric inference of
extreme value models for rainfall data, Water Resources Management, 24(6), 1229-
1249, doi: 10.1007/s11269-009-9493-3.
</p>
<p>4. AghaKouchak A., Habib E., 2010, Application of a conceptual hydrologic model in
teaching hydrologic processes, International Journal of Engineering Education, 26(4),
963-973.
</p>
<p>3. AghaKouchak A., Ciach G., Habib E., 2010, Estimation of tail dependence coefficient
in rainfall accumulation fields, Advances in Water resources, 33(9), 1142-1149, doi:
10.1016/j.advwatres.2010.07.003.
</p>
<p>2. AghaKouchak A., Habib E., Bárdossy A., 2010, A comparison of three remotely
sensed rainfall ensemble generators, Atmospheric Research, 98(2-4), 387-399, doi:
10.1016/j.atmosres.2010.07.016.
</p>
<p>1. AghaKouchak A., Nasrollahi, N., Habib, E., 2009, Accounting for Uncertainties of the
TRMM Satellite Estimates, Remote Sensing, 1(3), 606-619, doi: 10.3390/rs1030606.
</p>
<p>Books
</p>
<p>3. AghaKouchak A., Easterling D., Hsu K., Schubert S., Sorooshian S., Extremes in a
Changing Climate, Springer Netherlands, Dordrecht, ISBN 978-94-007-4478-3.
</p>
<p>2. AghaKouchak A., 2010, Simulation of Remotely Sensed Rainfall Fields Using Copulas,
University of Stuttgart, ISBN 978-3-933761-92-7.
</p>
<p>1. AghaKouchak A., Nasrollahi N., Firouz Bahadori, 2002, Engineering Hydrology: Prac-
tice Questions and Answers, Angizeh, ISBN 964-7517-03-3 (in Persian).
</p>
<p>Book Chapters
</p>
<p>7. Amir AghaKouchak, Zengchao Hao, Navid Nakhjiri, Lisa Damberg, 2013, Droughts,
Invited Book Chapter in: Encyclopedia of Natural Hazards, Taylor &amp; Francis, accepted.
</p>
<p>6. Sorooshian S., Nguyen P., Sellars S., Braithwaite D., AghaKouchak A., Hsu, K., 2014,
Satellite-based Remote Sensing Estimation of Precipitation for Early Warning Systems,
Book Chapter in: Extreme Natural Hazards, Disaster Risks and Societal Implications
(eds. Ismail-Zadeh A., Fucugaughi J. , Kijko A., Takeuchi K., Zaliapin I.), Cambridge
University Press, ISBN: 9781107033863.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 10
</p>
<p>5. AghaKouchak A., Sorooshian S., Hsu K., Gao X., 2013, The Potential of Precipitation Re-
mote Sensing for Water Resources Vulnerability Assessment in Arid Southwestern United
States, Invited Book Chapter in: Climate Vulnerability: Understanding and Addressing
Threats to Essential Resources - Water Encyclopedia (eds. Hossain and Pielke), Elsevier,
Academic Press, 141U˝149 pp., ISBN: 9780123847034.
</p>
<p>4. AghaKouchak A., Sellars S., Sorooshian S., Methods of Tail Dependence Estimation, In:
Extremes in a Changing Climate (eds. AghaKouchak A., Easterling D., Hsu K., Schubert
S. and Sorooshian S.), Springer Netherlands, Dordrecht, ISBN 978-94-007-4478-3.
</p>
<p>3. Amir AghaKouchak, Kuolin Hsu, Soroosh Sorooshian, Xiaogang Gao, Bisher Imam,
2012, Precipitation Estimation from Remotely Sensed Information using the Artificial
Neural Networks Algorithm: Application to Drought Monitoring and Analysis, Book
Chapter in: Remote Sensing of Drought - Innovative Monitoring Approaches (eds. B.
Wardlow, M. Anderson, J. Verdin), CRC Press, ISBN: 978-1439835579.
</p>
<p>2. Soroosh Sorooshian, Amir AghaKouchak, 2011, Advancement towards a state-of-the-
art hydrologic flood forecasting system, Invited Book Chapter in: Korea Environmental
Institute Book Series, Korea Institute of Construction Technology (KICT).
</p>
<p>1. Hengl T., AghaKouchak A., Percˇec Tadic´ M., 2010, Methods and data sources for spatial
prediction of rainfall, Book Chapter in Rainfall: State of the Science (eds. Testik F.Y. and
Gebremichael M.), American Geophysical Union, ISBN: 978-0-87590-481-8.
</p>
<p>Technical Reports, White Papers, and Other Publications
</p>
<p>11. Mirchi A., Madani K., Amir AghaKouchak, 2015, Lake Urmia: how Iran’s most famous
lake is disappearing, The Guardian, Friday 23 January 2015, View Article: http://gu.
com/p/455zb/tw
</p>
<p>10. Hoerling M., Schubert S., Mo K., AghaKouchak A., Berbery H., Dong J., Kumar A.,
Lakshmi V., Leung R., Li J., Liang X., Luo L., Lyon B., Miskus D., Quan X., Seager R.,
Sorooshian S., Wang H., Xia Y., Zeng N., 2013, An Interpretation of the Origins of the
2012 Central Great Plains Drought, Assessment Report, NOAA Drought Task Force Nar-
rative Team, Office of Oceanic and Atmsopheric Research, Climate Program Office.
</p>
<p>9. Kuolin Hsu, Soroosh Sorooshian, Xiaogang Gao, Dan Braithwaite, Amir AghaKouchak,
2012, Monitoring global precipitation using satellites, SPIE Newsroom.
</p>
<p>8. Christa Peters-Lidard, Ana Barros, Wade Crow, Witold Krajewski, Robert Houze, Walt Pe-
tersen, Amir AghaKouchak, Manos Anagnostou, Eyal Amitai, Rafael Bras, Robert Cifelli,
David Gochis, David C. Goodrich, Kuolin Hsu, Dennis Lettenmaier, Douglas Miller, Timo-
thy Schneider, Marshall Shepherd, James Smith, Soroosh Sorooshian, Ali Tokay, Jingfeng
Wang, Xubin Zeng, 2011, Global Precipitation Mission (GPM) Integrated Hydrologic
Ground Validation Science Implementation Plan, PMM Hydrology Working Group, God-
dard Space Flight Center, Greenbelt, MD.</p>
<p/>
<div class="annotation"><a href="http://gu.com/p/455zb/tw"/></div>
<div class="annotation"><a href="http://gu.com/p/455zb/tw"/></div>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 11
</p>
<p>7. NOWCAST ARTICLE: Sorooshian S., AghaKouchak A., Arkin P., Eylander J., Foufoula-
Georgiou E., Harmon R., Hendrickx J., Hsu K., Imam B., Kuligowski R., Skahill B.,
Skofronick-Jackson G., 2011, Advancing the Remote Sensing of Precipitation, Bulletin of
the American Meteorological Society - Nowcast, 92 (10), 1271-1272 doi: 10.1175/BAMS-
D-11-00116.1.
</p>
<p>6. Wade T. Crow, Kuolin Hsu, Jingfeng Wang, Amir AghaKouchak, Eyal Amitai, Rafael
Bras, David Gochis, David C. Goodrich, Soroosh Sorooshian, and Xubin Zeng, 2011,
Potential GPM Ground Validation Activities within the Semi-Arid Walnut Gulch/Upper
San Pedro River Basin, White Paper submitted to the Global Precipitation Mission (GPM)
Ground Validation Program, NASA GSFC, Greenbelt, MD.
</p>
<p>5. Sorooshian S., AghaKouchak A., Hsu K., Gao X., 2011, Annual Report: Satellite Data
Support for Hydrologic and Water Resource Planning and Management, University of
California Irvine, submitted to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration,
National Environmental Satellite Data and Information Service, National Climatic Data
Center.
</p>
<p>4. Sorooshian S., AghaKouchak A., Hsu K., Gao X., Imam B., 2010, Annual Report: Satel-
lite Data Support for Hydrologic and Water Resource Planning and Management, Univer-
sity of California Irvine, submitted to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administra-
tion, National Environmental Satellite Data and Information Service, National Climatic
Data Center.
</p>
<p>3. Amir AghaKouchak, Soroosh Sorooshian, 2010, Workshop Report: Advanced Concepts
on Remote Sensing of Precipitation at Multiple Scales, University of California Irvine,
March 15-17, 2010.
</p>
<p>2. AghaKouchak A., Sorooshian S., Imam B., Hsu K., Gao X., 2010, NASA Satellites Help
Monitor the Pakistan Flooding: An Application of Near-Real-Time Satellite Observations,
The Earth Observer, 22 (6), 4-6.
</p>
<p>1. Contributing author to the Wold Climate Research Program (WCRP) White Paper on
Drought Predictability and Prediction in a Changing Climate: Assessing Current Predic-
tive Knowledge and Capabilities, User Requirements and Research Priorities.
</p>
<p>Scientific &amp; Educational Software
</p>
<p>5. Non-stationary Extreme Value Analysis (NEVA) Toolbox:
By Linyin Cheng, and Amir AghaKouchak
URL: http://amir.eng.uci.edu/neva.php
</p>
<p>4. Standardized Drought Analysis Toolbox (SDAT):
By Alireza Farahmand, and Amir AghaKouchak
URL: http://amir.eng.uci.edu/sdat.php</p>
<p/>
<div class="annotation"><a href="http://amir.eng.uci.edu/neva.php"/></div>
<div class="annotation"><a href="http://amir.eng.uci.edu/sdat.php"/></div>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 12
</p>
<p>3. Validation Toolbox: Performance Metrics for Evaluation of Remote Sensing Observa-
tions and Climate Model Simulations
By Amir AghaKouchak and Ali Mehran
URL: http://amir.eng.uci.edu/downloads/ValidationToolbox.zip
</p>
<p>2. HBV-EDU: A MATLAB Hands-on Toolbox for Teaching Hydrologic Processes
By Amir AghaKouchak and Emad Habib
URL: http://amir.eng.uci.edu/education.html
</p>
<p>1. HBV-Ensemble: A MATLAB Toolbox for Ensemble Streamflow Simulation
By Amir AghaKouchak, Navid Nakhjiri, and Emad Habib
URL: http://amir.eng.uci.edu/downloads/HBV_Ensemble.zip
</p>
<p>Service, Committee &amp; Panel Assignments
</p>
<p>National and International
</p>
<p>Ad-hoc proposal reviewer for NSF, NASA, ARL and DOI.
</p>
<p>Co-Chair, The 2015 United States Frontiers of Engineering, National Academy of Engineer-
ing (NAE) of the National Academies.
</p>
<p>Secretary of Natural Hazards 2015 (elected), American Geophysical Union.
</p>
<p>Member, Visiting International Fellow (VIF) Technical Committee, Environmental and Wa-
ter Resources Institute (EWRI), American Society of Civil Engineers, 2015-present.
</p>
<p>Horton Research Grant Committee, American Geophysical Union (AGU), 2015.
</p>
<p>Member of the NOAA Drought Task Force (2014-2017).
</p>
<p>Proposal Review Panel, NSF Graduate Research Fellowships Program (GRFP), 2015.
</p>
<p>Proposal Review Panel, National Science Foundation (NSF), 2014.
</p>
<p>Proposal Review Panel, NSF Graduate Research Fellowships Program (GRFP), 2014.
</p>
<p>Graduate Student Award Committee, American Geophysical Union (AGU), Natural Haz-
ards Focus Group, 2014.
</p>
<p>Chair of the Organizing Committee, IAHS Summer School Copulas for Hydrology and Cli-
mate, 28 Jul - 1 Aug 2014, University of California, Irvine, USA.
</p>
<p>Member, Coordinated Energy and Water Cycle Observations Project (CEOP), Global Energy
and Water Cycle Experiment (GEWEX) Extremes Work Group.
</p>
<p>Member, Drought Interest Group (DIG), Climate Variability and Predictability Project (CLI-
VAR).
</p>
<p>Vice President of the IAHR Student Chapter, University of Stuttgart, 2006-2008</p>
<p/>
<div class="annotation"><a href="http://amir.eng.uci.edu/downloads/ValidationToolbox.zip"/></div>
<div class="annotation"><a href="http://amir.eng.uci.edu/education.html"/></div>
<div class="annotation"><a href="http://amir.eng.uci.edu/downloads/HBV_Ensemble.zip"/></div>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 13
</p>
<p>Project Coordinator of the IAHR Student Chapter, University of Stuttgart, 2005-2006
</p>
<p>Vice President of the Student Science Council, Department of Civil Engineering, K.N.Toosi
University of Technology, 2003-2004
</p>
<p>Member of the Editorial Board, Abangan Student Water Engineering Journal, Department
of Civil Engineering, K.N.Toosi University of Technology, 1999-2002
</p>
<p>Conference/Session Chair, Convener, or Moderator
</p>
<p>Co-Convener of the session Science for Disaster Risk Reduction: From Integrated Research
and Assessment of Risks to Communication and Engagements, AGU Fall Meeting, 14-18
Dec 2015, San Francisco, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Co-Convener of the session Advances in Remote Sensing of Natural Hazards, AGU Fall
Meeting, 14-18 Dec 2015, San Francisco, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Co-Convener of the session Monitoring, Prediction, and Hazard Mitigation of Hydrocli-
matic Extreme Events, AGU Fall Meeting, 14-18 Dec 2015, San Francisco, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Moderator, Session on Adaptive Management and Impact Assessment, ASCE, World Envi-
ronmental &amp; Water Resources Congress, Austin TX, Austin, Texas, USA, May 17-21, 2015.
</p>
<p>Co-Chair of the Scientific Committee, California Drought: Causes, Impacts, and Policy,
AGU Chapman Conference, Beckman Center of the National Academies of Sciences and
Engineering, Irvine, California, USA, April 20-22, 2015.
</p>
<p>Convener of the session Hydroclimatic Extremes: Drought, AGU Fall Meeting, 15-19 Dec
2014, San Francisco, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Convener of the session Satellite Remote Sensing and Management of Natural Disasters,
AGU Fall Meeting, 15-19 Dec 2014, San Francisco, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Convener of the session Sustainable Water Quantity and Quality in the Built Environment,
AGU Fall Meeting, 15-19 Dec 2014, San Francisco, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Member of the Scientific Committee, IAHS 5th STAHY workshop, 10-11 Nov 2014, Abu
Dhabi, United Arab Emirates.
</p>
<p>Technical Committee, 2013 ASCE International Workshop on Computing in Civil Engineer-
ing, June 23-25, 2013, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Convener of the session Hydrohazards: Processes, Diagnosis and Projection, AGU Fall
Meeting, 3-7 Dec 2012, San Francisco, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Convener of the session Hydroclimatic Extremes: Monitoring, Diagnosis &amp; Prediction, AGU
Fall Meeting, 5-9 Dec 2011, San Francisco, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Convener of the session Hydroclimatic Extremes: Monitoring, Diagnosis &amp; Prediction, AGU
Fall Meeting, 13-17 Dec 2010, San Francisco, CA, USA.
</p>
<p>Co-convener and coordinator, Advanced Concepts Workshop on Remote Sensing of Pre-
cipitation at Multiple Scales, March 15-17, 2010, University of California Irvine, Beckman
Center, Irvine, CA, USA.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 14
</p>
<p>Member of the Scientific Committee, 7th IWA Biennial World Water Congress, 19-24 Septem-
ber 2010, Montreal, Canada.
</p>
<p>Member of the organizing committee of the IAHR-SSC 2007 Colloquium: Hydraulic Engi-
neering and Renewable Energy, 31 October 2007, Stuttgart, Germany.
</p>
<p>Member of the organizing committee of the IAHR-SSC 2006 Colloquium: Integrated Sur-
face Water Management, 5 July 2006, Stuttgart, Germany.
</p>
<p>Member of the Organizing Committee, International Conference on Hydraulics of Dams
and Rivers Structures, Tehran, 26-28 April 2004
</p>
<p>University of California, Irvine
</p>
<p>Graduate Advisor, 2012 - Present
</p>
<p>Faculty Search Committee Member, 2013-2014
</p>
<p>Edison Scholarship Selection Committee, California Alliance for Minority Participation,
2014 and 2015
</p>
<p>Environmental Engineering Seminar Series, Organizer of Hydrology Talks, 2011-2013
</p>
<p>Graduate and Postdoctoral Advisees
</p>
<p>Postdoctoral Scholars
</p>
<p>Hamed Moftakhari Rostamkhani (2015 - present).
Shahrbanou Madadgar (2014 - present).
Zengchao Hao (2012 - 2013).
</p>
<p>PhD Students (Advisor, and Committee Chair)
</p>
<p>Ali Mehran, PhD, 2015.
Linyin Cheng, PhD, 2014.
Alireza Farahmand, PhD Student, 2011 - present.
Elisa Ragno, PhD Student, 2014 - present.
Omid Mazdiyasni, 2014 - present.
Charlotte Love, PhD Student, 2015 - present.
Felicia Chiang, PhD Student, 2015 - present.
</p>
<p>PhD Students (Co-Advisor)
</p>
<p>Phu Nguyen, PhD, 2014 (Advisor: S Sorooshian).
Jingjing Li, PhD, 2012 (Advisor: S Sorooshian).</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 15
</p>
<p>MS Students (Advisor, and Committee Chair)
</p>
<p>Mohsen Niknejad, 2015.
Omid Mazdiyasni, 2015.
Lei Li, 2015.
Zhu Liu, 2014.
Lisa Damberg MSc, 2013.
Alireza Farahmand MSc, 2013.
Hassan Anjileli, 2014 - present.
Juan Diego Rivadeneira, 2015 - present.
</p>
<p>PhD Dissertation Committee Member
</p>
<p>Masoud Irannezhad PhD, 2015, University of Oulu, Finland, (Advisors: Bjørn Kløve).
Hussein Wazneh PhD, 2015, Institut national de la recherche scientifique - Eau Terre
</p>
<p>Environnement (INRS-ETE), Québec, Canada, (Advisors: F Chebana).
Hao Liu PhD, 2015 (Advisor: S Sorooshian).
Mojtaba Sadegh PhD, 2015 (Advisor: J Vrugt).
Sasha Richey PhD, 2014 (Advisor: J Famiglietti).
Shakiba Ayatollahi PhD, 2013 (Advisor: W Cooper).
Marzi Azarderakhsh PhD, 2011, City University of New York (Advisors: W Rossow, R
</p>
<p>Khanbilvardi).
</p>
<p>Teaching Experience
</p>
<p>CEE 274: Climate Data Analysis (graduate), UC-Irvine, (2015, 2014).
</p>
<p>CEE 173 and CEE 273: Watershed Modeling (undergraduate, graduate), UC-Irvine,
(2015, 2014, 2013, 2012, 2011).
</p>
<p>CEE 81B: Civil Engineering Practicum II (undergraduate), UC-Irvine, (2015, 2014, 2013,
2012).
</p>
<p>CEE 176 and CEE 276: Hydrology (undergraduate, graduate), UC-Irvine, (2012).
</p>
<p>CEE 195: Introduction to Surveying (undergraduate), UC-Irvine, (2012).
</p>
<p>Invited Talks, Invited Lectures, Summer Schools
</p>
<p>30. Amir AghaKouchak, Anthropogenic Drought: A Global-Local Perspective, Santa Monica
Public Library, July 29, 2015.
</p>
<p>29. Amir AghaKouchak, Madadgar S., Cheng L., Shukla S., Wood A., Svoboda M., Improv-
ing seasonal precipitation forecasting in California through integration of dynamic and
statistical models, NOAA Modeling, Analysis, Predictions, and Projections (MAPP) We-
binar Series, June 9, 2015.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 16
</p>
<p>28. Amir AghaKouchak, Madadgar S., Cheng L., Shukla S., Advancing Drought Prediction
Using an Analog-Year Model Combined with Dynamic Model Simulations, Western States
Water Council Workshop on Sub-Seasonal and Seasonal Precipitation Forecasting, San
Diego, CA, USA, May 27-29, 2015.
</p>
<p>27. Amir AghaKouchak, Invited lectures on Integrated Water Cycle Analysis, 3rd Workshop
on Water Resources in Developing Countries: Planning and Management in Face of Hy-
droclimatological Extremes and Variability, International Centre for Theoretical Physics
(ICTP), Trieste, Italy, April 27-30, 2015.
</p>
<p>26. Amir AghaKouchak, Water Scarcity Iran: Challenges and Opportunities, US-Iran Sym-
posium on Climate Change: Impacts and Mitigation, Beckman Center of the National
Academies of Sciences and Engineering, March 30 - April 1, 2015.
</p>
<p>25. AghaKouchak A., Farahmand A., Drought Monitoring Using NASA Atmospheric Infrared
Sounder (AIRS) Data, NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL), Pasadena, California, USA,
March 25, 2015.
</p>
<p>24. Amir AghaKouchak, Drought and Water Stress Assessment, Transforming Stormwater
into a Resource: Design, Risks, and Benefits, New Delhi, India, March 16-17, 2015.
</p>
<p>23. Amir AghaKouchak, Advancing Drought Onset Detection and Seasonal Prediction Using
a Composite of NASA Model and Satellite Data, NASA Applied Sciences Program, Water
Resources Meeting, College Park, Maryland, USA, March 3-4, 2015.
</p>
<p>22. Amir AghaKouchak, Global Integrated Drought Monitoring and Prediction System (GIDMaPS),
An International Global Drought Information System Workshop: Next Steps, California
Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA, USA, December 11-13, 2014.
</p>
<p>21. Amir AghaKouchak, Monitoring Endangered Ecosystems from Space, Eighth Annual
Meeting of the US-China EcoPartnership on Wetlands, Beckman Center of the National
Academies of Sciences and Engineering, December 8, 2014.
</p>
<p>20. Amir AghaKouchak, Remote Sensing Applications for Drought Monitoring, Interna-
tional Expert Symposium "Building a Community of Practice on Drought Management
Tools", Santiago, Chile, November 19-21, 2014.
</p>
<p>19. AghaKouchak A., The 2014 California Drought: Opportunities for Drought-Proofing
California, Civil and Environmental Engineering Fall Quarterly Meeting, UCI University
Club, November 7, 2014.
</p>
<p>18. AghaKouchak A., IAHS Summer School Copulas for Hydrology and Climate, Jul 28 -
Aug 1, 2014, University of California, Irvine, USA.
</p>
<p>17. AghaKouchak A., California Drought: How Bad is It?, UC Drought Summit, Sacramento,
California, April 25, 2014.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 17
</p>
<p>16. AghaKouchak A., Farahmand A., Nakhjiri N., Advancing Global Drought Monitoring and
Prediction Using GPM Data, NASA’s Global Precipitation Mission Land Surface Working
Group, March 7, 2014.
</p>
<p>15. AghaKouchak A., Advancing Global Drought Monitoring and Prediction: Introducing
GIDMaPS, NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL), Pasadena, California, USA, January
29, 2014.
</p>
<p>14. AghaKouchak A., Mehran A., Global Terrestrial Hydrologic Modeling: Roadblocks, Chal-
lenges and Opportunities, AGU Fall Meeting, San Francisco, California, USA, December
9-13, 2013.
</p>
<p>13. AghaKouchak A., Monitoring Extremes, Southern California Society for Risk Analysis,
October 21, 2013, Irvine, California, USA.
</p>
<p>12. Amir AghaKouchak, Advancing Global Drought Monitoring and Prediction: An Overview
of GIDMaPS, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida, September 17, 2013.
</p>
<p>11. Amir AghaKouchak, The Global Integrated Drought Monitoring and Prediction System
(GIDMaPS), The Desert Research Workshop, Beckman Center of the National Academies
of Sciences and Engineering, June 5, 2013.
</p>
<p>10. Amir AghaKouchak, Invited lectures on Integrated Water Cycle Analysis, 2nd Workshop
on Water Resources in Developing Countries: Planning and Management in a Climate
Change Scenario, International Centre for Theoretical Physics (ICTP), Trieste, Italy, May
6-17, 2013.
</p>
<p>9. Amir AghaKouchak, Zengchao Hao, Navid Nakhjiri, Multi-Index Drought Monitoring:
A Prototype Global Drought GeoServer, American Geophysical Union (AGU) Meeting of
the Americas, Cancun, Mexico, 14-17 May 2013.
</p>
<p>8. Amir AghaKouchak, Middle East Hydroclimate Extremes, Groundwater and Climate
Change in the Middle East, Beckman Center of the National Academies of Sciences and
Engineering, November 9-11, 2012.
</p>
<p>7. Amir AghaKouchak, A Nested Hydrological Model for Coupled Probabilistic and Deter-
ministic Flood Forecasting, NOAA Center for Cooperative Remote Sensing Sciences and
Technology(CREST), The City College of the City University of New York, New York, NY,
September 19, 2011.
</p>
<p>6. Amir AghaKouchak, Soroosh Sorooshian, Kuolin Hsu, Application of Remotely Sensed
Precipitation Data in Monitoring and Analysis of Extremes: Challenges and Opportuni-
ties; In Drought Research Initiative Workshop on Weather and Climate Extremes over
Canada: Science and Adaptation, Winnipeg, Canada, February 7-9, 2011
</p>
<p>5. Amir AghaKouchak, Kuolin Hsu, Soroosh Sorooshian, Satellite Data Support for Hydro-
logic and Water Resource Planning and Management, Cooperative Institute for Climate
and Satellites (CICS) Science Meeting, University of Maryland, College Park, September
8-9, 2010.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 18
</p>
<p>4. Amir AghaKouchak, Remote Sensing of Rainfall, UCI Extension Osher Lifelong Learning
Institute fall class on Water Research at UCI, University of California Irvine, September
23, 2010.
</p>
<p>3. Amir AghaKouchak, Verification of satellite-based extreme precipitation estimates, NASA
Energy and Water cycle Study (NEWS) Extreme Drought and Flood Workshop, Univer-
sity of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND, July 15-16, 2010.
</p>
<p>2. Amir AghaKouchak, Kuolin Hsu, Analysis of Extreme Precipitation Events in a Chang-
ing Climate: Toward Capturing Nonstationarity, NOAA’s National Climatic Data Center,
Asheville, NC, April 6, 2010.
</p>
<p>1. Amir AghaKouchak, Iran’s Climate Change, Environmental and Water Resources Chal-
lenges, Samuel Jordan Center for Persian Studies, University of California, Irvine, Novem-
ber 8, 2010.
</p>
<p>Conference Presentations and Abstracts
</p>
<p>74. Cheng L., Ragno E., Xue Cui, AghaKouchak A., International Conference on Advances in
Extreme Value Analysis and Application to Natural Hazards, Universidad de Cantabria,
September 16-18, 2015, Santander, Spain.
</p>
<p>73. Tarroja B., AghaKouchak A., Samuelsen S., The Greenhouse Gas Intensity of Alternative
Water Resources, ASME Power &amp; Energy 2015, July 2, 2015, San Diego, CA, USA
</p>
<p>72. AghaKouchak A., Nonstationarity in Climate and Increased Flood Risk in a Changing
Climate, ASCE WORLD Environmental &amp; Water Resources Congress 2015, May 17-21,
2015, Austin, Texas, USA.
</p>
<p>71. AghaKouchak A., Drought Monitoring: Challenges &amp; Opportunities to Enhance Califor-
nia’s Resilience to Drought, AGU Chapman Conference on California Drought: Causes,
Impacts, and Policy, Beckman Center of the National Academies of Sciences and Engi-
neering, April 20-22, 2015, Irvine, California, USA.
</p>
<p>70. AghaKouchak A., Tourian M.J., Multi-Sensor Drought Monitoring, Prediction and Re-
covery Assessment Using Gravimetry Information, European Geosciences Union General
Assembly 2015, April 12-17, 2015, Vienna, Austria.
</p>
<p>69. AghaKouchak A., Tourian M.J., A Drought Cyberinfrastructure System for Improving
Water Resource Management and Policy Making, European Geosciences Union General
Assembly 2015, April 12-17, 2015, Vienna, Austria.
</p>
<p>68. Cheng L., Rajagopalan B., Bracken C., AghaKouchak A., A Generalized Spatio-temporal
Framework for Climate Informed Extreme Precipitation Analysis, AGU Hydrology Days,
March 23-25, 2015, Boulder, Colorado, USA.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 19
</p>
<p>67. Chen Y., Norouzi H., AghaKouchak A., BhambriM., Blake DR., Detection of Land Cover
Change and Drought Trend Using Brightness Temperature and Microwave Emission,
AMS Annual Meeting, January 4-8, 2015, Phoenix, Arizona, USA.
</p>
<p>66. AghaKouchak A., Feldman D., Grant S., Farahmand A., Nakhjiri N., Momtaz F., Toward
a Drought Cyberinfrastructure System for Improving Water Resource Management and
Policy Making, AGU Fall Meeting, December 15-19, 2014, San Francisco, California,
USA.
</p>
<p>65. Mazdiyasni O., AghaKouchak A., Changes in Concurrent Droughts and Heatwaves in
the United States, AGU Fall Meeting, December 15-19, 2014, San Francisco, California,
USA.
</p>
<p>64. Mehran A., AghaKouchak A., Water Resources Vulnerability Assessment Accounting for
Human Influence, AGU Fall Meeting, December 15-19, 2014, San Francisco, California,
USA.
</p>
<p>63. Ragno E., AghaKouchak A., Trends and Patterns of Change in Temperature and Evapo-
ration, AGU Fall Meeting, December 15-19, 2014, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>62. Farahmand A., AghaKouchak A., Improving early drought detection using satellite-
based relative humidity data, AGU Fall Meeting, December 15-19, 2014, San Francisco,
California, USA.
</p>
<p>61. AghaKouchak A., Nakhjiri N., Habib E., An Educational Model for Hands-On Hydrology
Education, AGU Fall Meeting, December 15-19, 2014, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>60. Cheng L., AghaKouchak A., An Empirical Bayes Framework for Assessing Changes in the
Hydrological Cycle, AGU Fall Meeting, December 15-19, 2014, San Francisco, California,
USA.
</p>
<p>59. Nguyen P., Thorstensen A., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., Sanders B., Sorooshian S., Simu-
lation of the 2008 Iowa Flood using HiResFlood-UCI Model with Remote Sensing Data,
AGU Fall Meeting, December 15-19, 2014, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>58. Luke A., Schubert S., Cheng L., AghaKouchak A., Sanders B., Predicting Flood Hazards
in Systems with Multiple Flooding Mechanisms, AGU Fall Meeting, December 15-19,
2014, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>57. Chen Y., Bhambri M., Norouzi H., AghaKouchak A., Potential of Using Microwave Emis-
sion in Global Analysis of Land Cover and Drought State, AGU Fall Meeting, December
15-19, 2014, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>56. AghaKouchak A., Cheng L., Introducing the Non-stationary Extreme Value Analysis
(NEVA), IAHS STAHY2014 Workshop, November 10-11, 2014, Abu-Dhabi.
</p>
<p>55. AghaKouchak A., A Multi-Index Framework for Global Drought Monitoring and Predic-
tion, IAHS STAHY2014 Workshop, November 10-11, 2014, Abu-Dhabi.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 20
</p>
<p>54. AghaKouchak A., Improving Early Drought Detection Using AIRS Satellite Observations,
2015 EUMETSAT Meteorological Satellite Conference, September 21-25, 2015, Geneva
Switzerland.
</p>
<p>53. AghaKouchak A., A Copula-Based Multi-Index Approach for Global Drought Monitoring
and Prediction, Spatial Copula Workshop, September 22-23, 2014, University of Mun-
ster, Germany.
</p>
<p>52. Nguyen P., Thorstensen A., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., Sanders B., Sorooshian S., Devel-
oping a Global High-Resolution Flash Flood Forecasting System Using Multiple Sources
of Precipitation Data, AGS Symposium, April 15, 2014, Irvine, California, USA.
</p>
<p>51. AghaKouchak A., Hao Z., Farahmand A., Nakhjiri A., The Global Integrated Drought
Monitoring and Prediction System (GIDMaPS): Overview and Capabilities, AGU Fall
Meeting, December 9-13, 2013, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>50. Cheng L., Gilleland E., AghaKouchak A., Nonstationary Extreme Value Analysis in a
Changing Climate: A Software Package, AGU Fall Meeting, December 9-13, 2013, San
Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>49. Hao Z., AghaKouchak A., Predicting the 2012 U.S. Summer Drought Using a Persistence
Method, AGU Fall Meeting, December 9-13, 2013, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>48. Mehran A., AghaKouchak A., Phillips T.J., Performance Metrics for Climate Model Eval-
uation: Application to CMIP5 Precipitation Simulations, AGU Fall Meeting, December
9-13, 2013, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>47. Liu Z., Mehran A., Phillips T.J., AghaKouchak A., Seasonal and Regional Biases in CMIP5
Precipitation Simulation, AGU Fall Meeting, December 9-13, 2013, San Francisco, Cali-
fornia, USA.
</p>
<p>46. Norouzi H., AghaKouchak A., Madani K., Mirchi A., Farahmand F., Conway C., Monitor-
ing Changes in Water Resources Systems Using High Resolution Satellite Observations:
Application to Lake Urmia, AGU Fall Meeting, December 9-13, 2013, San Francisco,
California, USA.
</p>
<p>45. Nguyen P., Sorooshian S., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., Sanders B., Evaluating the Perfor-
mance of a Coupled Distributed Hydrologic-Hydraulic Model for Flash Flood Modeling
Using Multiple Precipitation Data Sources, December 9-13, 2013, San Francisco, Cali-
fornia, USA.
</p>
<p>44. Hao Z., AghaKouchak A., Global Drought Monitoring and Prediction Data Products,
Next Generation Climate Data Products Workshop, National Center for Atmospheric Re-
search, July 15-19, 2013, Boulder, Colorado, USA.
</p>
<p>43. Nguyen P., Sorooshian S., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., ArcGIS for a Coupled Hydrologic-
Hydraulic Modeling, Esri International User Conference, July 8-12, 2013, San Diego,
California, USA.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 21
</p>
<p>42. Nguyen P., Sorooshian S., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., Sanders B., Modeling the Upper
Little Missouri River 2010 Flash Flood Using a Coupled Distributed Hydrologic and Hy-
draulic Model, Community Surface Dynamics Modeling System (CSDMS) 2013 Annual
Meeting, March 23-25, Boulder, Colorado, USA.
</p>
<p>41. AghaKouchak A., A Multivariate Multi-Index Drought Monitoring and Prediction Frame-
work, NOAA Drought Task Force, Webinar Series Drought I (Understanding and Moni-
toring), February 12, 2013, USA.
</p>
<p>40. AghaKouchak A., Hao Z., Multi-Index Drought Monitoring Using NASA MERRA Data,
International Union of Geodesy and Geophysics (IUGG) Geophysical Risk and Sustain-
ability (GeoRisk) Conference on Extreme Natural Hazards and their Impacts. December
8-11, 2012, Chapman University, Orange, California, USA.
</p>
<p>39. Nguyen P., Sorooshian S., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., Sanders B., A Coupled Distributed
Hydrologic and Hydraulic Model for Flash Flood Modeling, International Union of Geodesy
and Geophysics (IUGG) Geophysical Risk and Sustainability (GeoRisk) Conference on
Extreme Natural Hazards and their Impacts. December 8-11, 2012, Chapman Univer-
sity, Orange, California, USA.
</p>
<p>38. AghaKouchak A., Hao Z., Climate Change Impacts on Droughts Severity-Area-Duration
across the Southwest United States, AGU Fall Meeting, December 3-7, 2012, San Fran-
cisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>37. Farahmand A., AghaKouchak A., A Quasi-Global Landslide Model Using Remote Sensing
Data, AGU Fall Meeting, December 3-7, 2012, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>36. Mehran A., Nakhjiri N., AghaKouchak A., A Nested Global-Local Hydrological Model
for Large Scale Flood Forecasting Using Satellite Data, AGU Fall Meeting, December 3-7,
2012, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>35. Hao Z., AghaKouchak A., A multivariate approach for drought monitoring across the
continental United States, AGU Fall Meeting, December 3-7, 2012, San Francisco, Cali-
fornia, USA.
</p>
<p>34. Cheng L., AghaKouchak A., Deriving Climate Response from CMIP5 Ensemble Climate
Projections: Application to Analysis of Temperature and Precipitation Extremes, AGU
Fall Meeting, December 3-7, 2012, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>33. Damberg L., AghaKouchak A., Changes in the Patterns and Trends of Droughts across
Land and Ocean, AGU Fall Meeting, December 3-7, 2012, San Francisco, California,
USA.
</p>
<p>32. Nguyen P., Sorooshian S., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., Sanders B., Smith M.B., Koren V.,
Improving flash flood forecasting through coupling of a distributed hydrologic rainfall-
runoff model (HL-RDHM) with a hydraulic model (BreZo), AGU Fall Meeting, December
3-7, 2012, San Francisco, California, USA.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 22
</p>
<p>31. Li J., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., Sorooshian S., Evaluation of satellite-based precipitation
estimates in winter season using an object-based approach, AGU Fall Meeting, December
3-7, 2012, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>30. AghaKouchak A., Mehran A., Nakhjiri N., 2012, A nested global-local hydrological
model for large scale flood forecasting using remote sensing satellite data: a contribution
to monitoring global environmental change, Proceedings of the SPIE - The International
Society for Optical Engineering, 29 October - 1 November 2012, SPIE Asia-Pacific Re-
mote Sensing, Kyoto, Japan.
</p>
<p>29. AghaKouchak A., Hao Z., A Multi-Index Standardized Drought Monitoring and Pre-
diction Framework, NOAA’s 37th Climate Diagnostics and Prediction Workshop, 22-25
October 2012. Fort Collins, Colorado, USA.
</p>
<p>28. AghaKouchak A., Hao Z., A Multi-Index multivariate Drought Monitoring Framework:
Application to Climate Change Impact Assessment, International Conference on Climate,
Water and Policy (ICCWP), 11-13 September 2012, Busan, South Korea.
</p>
<p>27. AghaKouchak A., Cheng L., Tracking and Nowcasting of Hurricanes: a Data Fusion
Approach, 3rd World Meteorological Organization (WMO) International Symposium on
Nowcasting (WSN12), 6-10 August 2012, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.
</p>
<p>26. David C. Goodrich, Eyal Amitai, Wade T. Crow, Kuolin Hsu, Jingfeng Wang, AghaK-
ouchak A., Rafael Bras, David Gochis, Soroosh Sorooshian, Xubin Zeng, Carl Unkrich,
Emad Habib, Bryson Thill, In-situ Verification of TRMM Radar Rainfall Intensity Esti-
mates and a Strategy for GPM Ground Validations in the Southwest, 5th International
Workshop for GPM Ground Validation, 10-12 July 12, 2012, Toronto, Canada.
</p>
<p>25. AghaKouchak A., A Drought GeoServer for Real-Time Drought Monitoring and Anal-
ysis, World Climate Research Programme (WCRP) Global Drought Information System
Workshop, Frascati, Italy, 11-13 April 2012, Frascati, Italy.
</p>
<p>24. AghaKouchak A., Sorooshian, S., 2012, Application of Satellite Data to Drought Moni-
toring and Analysis, Satellites for Better Water and Environment Management: A Train-
ing Session Hosted Jointly by The World Bank and U.S. Government Agencies Working
in Remote Sensing, February 29, 2012, Washington, DC.
</p>
<p>23. AghaKouchak A., A Nested Probabilistic and Deterministic Flood Forecasting Model: To-
ward an Early Warning System, AGU Fall Meeting, December 5-9, 2011, San Francisco,
California, USA.
</p>
<p>22. Li J., Hsu K., AghaKouchak A., Sorooshian S., A hybrid framework for verification of
satellite precipitation products, AGU Fall Meeting, December 5-9, 2011, San Francisco,
California, USA.
</p>
<p>21. David C Goodrich, Efrat Morin, Eyal Amitai, Carl Unkrich, Timothy Keefer, Jeffry Stone,
Mike Schaffner, Kuo-lin Hsu, Shayesteh E Mahani, Wade T Crow, Jingfeng Wang, Amir
AghaKouchak, David J Gochis, Soroosh Sorooshian, Rafael L Bras, Xubin Zeng, Pit</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 23
</p>
<p>Gauges to Satellites: Precipitation Retrievals over the USDA-ARS Walnut Gulch Exper-
imental Watershed, Arizona, AGU Fall Meeting, December 5-9, 2011, San Francisco,
California, USA.
</p>
<p>20. AghaKouchak A., Soroosh Sorooshian, Application of Satellite Data to Drought Moni-
toring and Analysis, World Climate Research Programme (WCRP) Workshop on Drought
Predictability and Prediction in a Changing Climate: Assessing Current Knowledge and
Capabilities, User Requirements and Research Priorities, March 2-4, 2011, Barcelona,
Spain.
</p>
<p>19. Behrangi A., Khakbaz B., Jaw T.,AghaKouchak A., Analyzing the performance of the
high resolution precipitation products for streamflow simulation, 25th Conference on
Hydrology, 91st Annual Meeting of the American Meteorological Society, Seattle, WA
23-27 January 2011.
</p>
<p>18. AghaKouchak A., Hsu K., Behrangi A., Sorooshian S., Error Decomposition in Satellite-
Derived Precipitation Estimates, AGU Fall Assembly, December 13-17, 2010, San Fran-
cisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>17. Feng Z., Dong X., Xi B., Minnis P., Khaiyer M., AghaKouchak A., Improving Satellite-
based Instantaneous Precipitation Estimate by Using Integration of Ground Radar and
Satellite Dataset, AGU Fall Assembly, December 13-17, 2010, San Francisco, California,
USA.
</p>
<p>16. AghaKouchak A., Hsu K., Sorooshian S., A Global Multi-Sensor Satellite-Based Gauge-
Adjusted Precipitation Data Set, NASA Precipitation Measurement Missions (PMM) Sci-
ence Team Meeting, November 1-4, 2010, Seattle, Washington.
</p>
<p>15. AghaKouchak A., Sorooshian S., Detecting Precipitation Extremes form Satellites, 2nd
Pan-GEWEX Science Meeting, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, 23-27 August
2010.
</p>
<p>14. Sorooshian S., AghaKouchak A., Nasrollahi N., Imam B., Gao X., Hsu K., Validation of
Satellite Precipitation Data in Capturing Extreme Climate Events, Western Pacific Geo-
physics Meeting, June 22-25, 2010, Taipei, Taiwan.
</p>
<p>13. AghaKouchak A., Bárdossy A., Habib E., An uncertainty model for radar-based multi-
sensor precipitation estimates: A non-Gaussian copula-based approach, AGU Fall Assem-
bly, December 14-18, 2009, San Francisco, California, USA.
</p>
<p>12. Ciach G., AghaKouchak A., Habib E., Estimation of tail dependence coefficient in rainfall
accumulation fields, AGU Fall Assembly, December 14-18, 2009, San Francisco, Califor-
nia, USA.
</p>
<p>11. Nasrollahi N., AghaKouchak A., Uncertainty of a Weather Prediction Model in Predict-
ing Extreme Rainfall Events: Application to Hurricane Rita, NOAA Fifth Education and
Science Forum, November 12-14, 2009, Washington DC, USA.</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 24
</p>
<p>10. AghaKouchak A., Uncertainty assessment of remotely sensed data using copulas, NOAA
Fifth Education and Science Forum, November 12-14, 2009, Washington DC, USA.
</p>
<p>9. AghaKouchak A., Simulation of multivariate random variables using a non-Gaussian
copula, Special Session on Stochastic Analysis and Applications, American Mathematical
Society Meeting, November 6-8, 2009, Riverside, California, USA.
</p>
<p>8. AghaKouchak A., Bárdossy A., Habib E., A Copula Based Space-Time Rainfall Simulation
Model, AGU Joint Assembly, May 27-30, 2008, Florida, USA.
</p>
<p>7. AghaKouchak A., Habib E., Simulation of radar rainfall errors and their propagation
into rainfall-runoff processes, AGU Joint Assembly, May 27-30, 2008, Florida, USA.
</p>
<p>6. AghaKouchak A., Bárdossy A., Characterization of rainfall patterns, 9th International
Precipitation Conference IPC9, Nov. 12-14, 2007, Paris, France.
</p>
<p>5. AghaKouchak A., Nasrollahi N., Schlabing D., Tuhtan J., Kavianpour M.R., Air-Water
Flow Analysis Using Numerical, Experimental and Simulated Annealing methods, 32nd
Congress of IAHR, July 1-6, 2007, Venice, Italy.
</p>
<p>4. Kavianpour M.R. , AghaKouchak A., Stochastical Characteristics of Hydrodynamic Pres-
sure on the Bed of Plunge Pools, International Symposium Stochastic Hydraulics Con-
ference (Editors Vrijling, J.K., Rurijgh, E., Stalenberg, B. Van Gelder, P.H.A.I.M., Verlaan,
M., Zijderveld, A., and Waarts), May 23-25, 2005, Nijmegen, The Netherlands, ISBN:
90-805649-9-0.
</p>
<p>3. AghaKouchak A., Kavianpour M.R., Sadeghi H.R., Numerical Investigation of Hydrody-
namic Force on Outlet Gates, In Proceeding of the 31st Congress of IAHR, VOL 1, pages
612-613, September 11-16, 2005, Seoul, Korea.
</p>
<p>2. Kavianpour M.R. , AghaKouchak A., Sadeghi H.R., Numerical Analysis of Flow within
Outlet Conduits, International Conference on Hydraulic Engineering: Research and Prac-
tice (ICON-HERP), October 26-28, 2004, Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee, India.
</p>
<p>1. Kavianpour M.R. , AghaKouchak A., Computational Analysis of Flow in Bottom Outlet
Conduits, In Environmental Hydraulics and Sustainable Water Management (Editors:
J.H.W. Lee; K.M. Lam): Proceedings of the 4th International Symposium on Environ-
mental Hydraulics &amp; 14th Congress of Asia and Pacific Division, International Associa-
tion of Hydraulic Engineering and Research, 15-18 December 2004, Hong Kong (ISBN:
9780415365468).
</p>
<p>Professional Societies
</p>
<p>American Geophysical Union (AGU)
</p>
<p>American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS)</p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p>Amir AghaKouchak, PhD, PE 25
</p>
<p>American Meteorological Society (AMS)
</p>
<p>European Geosciences Union (EGU)
</p>
<p>International Association of Hydrological Sciences (IAHS)
</p>
<p>International Association of Hydro-Environment Engineering and Research (IAHR)
</p>
<p>American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE)
</p>
<p>Brief CV: URL: http://amir.eng.uci.edu/cv.html</p>
<p/>
<div class="annotation"><a href="http://amir.eng.uci.edu/cv.html"/></div>
</div>
<ul>	<li>Current Position</li>
	<li>Professional Licensure</li>
	<li>Education</li>
	<li>Academic Experience</li>
	<li>Honors &amp; Awards</li>
	<li>Grants, Awards &amp; Projects</li>
	<li>Editorial</li>
	<li>Patent</li>
	<li>Publications</li>
	<li>Journal Publications</li>
	<li>Books</li>
	<li>Book Chapters</li>
	<li>Technical Reports and White Papers</li>
	<li>Scientific &amp; Educational Software</li>
	<li>Committee &amp; Panel Assignments</li>
	<li>National and International</li>
	<li>Conference/Session Chair/Convener/Moderator</li>
	<li>University of California, Irvine</li>
	<li>Graduate and Postdoctoral Advisees</li>
	<li>Postdoctoral Scholars</li>
	<li>PhD Students (Advisor)</li>
	<li>PhD Students (Co-Advisor)</li>
	<li>MS Students (Advisor)</li>
	<li>Teaching Experience</li>
	<li>Invited Talks</li>
	<li>Conference Presentations</li>
	<li>Professional Societies</li>
</ul>
</body></html>