<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
<meta name="pdf:PDFVersion" content="1.3"/>
<meta name="xmp:CreatorTool" content="PScript5.dll Version 5.2"/>
<meta name="access_permission:modify_annotations" content="true"/>
<meta name="access_permission:can_print_degraded" content="true"/>
<meta name="dc:creator" content="Amado"/>
<meta name="dcterms:created" content="2007-02-05T14:00:29Z"/>
<meta name="dc:format" content="application/pdf; version=1.3"/>
<meta name="access_permission:fill_in_form" content="true"/>
<meta name="pdf:encrypted" content="false"/>
<meta name="dc:title" content="Microsoft Word - CVTsoukiasweb.doc"/>
<meta name="Content-Length" content="71279"/>
<meta name="Content-Type" content="application/pdf"/>
<meta name="X-Parsed-By" content="org.apache.tika.parser.DefaultParser"/>
<meta name="X-Parsed-By" content="org.apache.tika.parser.pdf.PDFParser"/>
<meta name="creator" content="Amado"/>
<meta name="meta:author" content="Amado"/>
<meta name="meta:creation-date" content="2007-02-05T14:00:29Z"/>
<meta name="created" content="Mon Feb 05 06:00:29 PST 2007"/>
<meta name="access_permission:extract_for_accessibility" content="true"/>
<meta name="access_permission:assemble_document" content="true"/>
<meta name="xmpTPg:NPages" content="7"/>
<meta name="Creation-Date" content="2007-02-05T14:00:29Z"/>
<meta name="resourceName" content="CVTsoukiasweb.pdf"/>
<meta name="access_permission:extract_content" content="true"/>
<meta name="access_permission:can_print" content="true"/>
<meta name="Author" content="Amado"/>
<meta name="producer" content="GNU Ghostscript 7.06"/>
<meta name="access_permission:can_modify" content="true"/>
<title>Microsoft Word - CVTsoukiasweb.doc</title>
</head>
<body><div class="page"><p/>
<p> </p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>i 
</p>
<p>CURRICULUM VITAE (1/07) 
 
</p>
<p>NIKOLAOS M. TSOUKIAS 
Assistant Professor 
</p>
<p>Department of Biomedical Engineering 
Florida International University 
10555 W. Flagler Str., EC 2674 
</p>
<p>Miami, Florida 33174 
[Tel]: (305) 348-7291 
</p>
<p>[E-mail]: tsoukias@fiu.edu 
 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>EDUCATION 
 
</p>
<p>Ph.D.: Engineering, 1999 
 Dissertation Title: “Characterization of Nitric Oxide exchange in human lungs” 
 Dissertation Advisor: Steven C. George 
 University of California, Irvine 
 
</p>
<p>M.S.: Chemical &amp; Biochemical Engineering, 1997 
 University of California, Irvine 
 
</p>
<p>B.S.: Chemical Engineering, 1994 
 National Technical University, Athens, Greece 
 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>EMPLOYMENT  
 
</p>
<p>(2003-   ) Assistant Professor, Department of Biomedical Engineering, FLORIDA INTERNATIONAL 
UNIVERSITY, Miami.  
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>(2000-03 ) Postdoctoral Fellow, Center for Computational Medicine and Biology, Department of 
Biomedical Engineering, JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF MEDICINE, 
Baltimore.  
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>(2001-02) Lecturer, Whiting School of Engineering, JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY, Baltimore.  
 
</p>
<p>(1999-00) Postdoctoral Fellow, Department of Chemical and Biochemical Engineering UNIVERSITY OF 
CALIFORNIA, Irvine.  
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>HONORS &amp; AWARDS 
 
</p>
<p>• The 2006 Arthur Guyton Award for Excellence in Integrative Physiology  
 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> </p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p> </p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>ii 
</p>
<p>TEACHING  EXPERIENCE 
 
</p>
<p>• Mathematical Modeling of Physiological Systems. (BME 6715: FIU Graduate Course) 
• Mathematical Modeling of Cellular Systems. (BME 6716: FIU Graduate Course) 
• Nonlinear Systems in Life Sciences. (BME 6705: FIU Graduate Course) 
• Biomedical Engineering Modeling and Simulation. (BME 2740: FIU Undergraduate Course) 
• Senior Design Project. (BME: FIU Undergraduate Course) 
• Biological Fluid and Solid Mechanics. (Johns Hopkins Graduate Course) 
 
</p>
<p>RESEARCH  
 
</p>
<p>(2003- ) Fluorescence microscopy in isolated microvessels. 
 
</p>
<p>(2003- ) Design of novel Nitric Oxide therapeutics and administration strategies. 
 
</p>
<p>(2003- ) Modeling Calcium dynamics in the microcirculation. 
 
</p>
<p>(2000-  ) High Performance Computing simulations of oxygen transport in three-dimensional 
microvascular networks in the presence of hemoglobin-based blood substitutes. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>(2000-  ) Nitric Oxide transport in the microcirculation in the presence and absence of hemoglobin-based 
blood substitutes. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>(1999-00) Lung mechanics: Modeling the expiratory flow properties after laser or staple lung volume 
reduction surgery in emphysema.   
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>(1998-99) Measurement of the lung diffusing capacity for NO and CO and its dependence on alveolar 
volume.  Model development and experimental determination in healthy human subjects. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>(1997-00) Endogenous NO exchange dynamics in the lung.   
 
</p>
<p>(1997-00) Measurement of endogenous NO in exhaled breath of healthy and diseased human and animal 
subjects  
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>(1996-97) Computer simulation of ethanol exchange in the lungs  
 
</p>
<p>(1993-94) Heat and mass transfer in air-drying fruits and vegetables  
 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>ADVISEES 
 
</p>
<p>Postdoctoral Fellows 
• Adam Kapela (2005- ) 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>PhD Students  
• Joe Wu (2005- ) 
• Sabnam Namin (2006-) 
• Reshmi Banerjee (2006-) 
 
</p>
<p>MS Students (Thesis Option) </p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p> </p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>iii 
</p>
<p>• Manu Kanwar (2003-2005)  David Isaza (2003-2005) 
• Rohit Chawla (2004-2006)  Sara Nofalah (2005- ) 
 
</p>
<p>Undergraduate Students  
• Haroldo Silva (2003-2006 )  Jennifer Hall (2005-2006 ) 
• Luis Alonso  (2006-)   Roxana Ordonez (2006- ) 
• Adrian Gomez (2006-) 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>SERVICE AND MEMBERSHIPS 
 
</p>
<p>Memberships: 
• American Heart Association (AHA) 
• American Physiological Society (APS) 
• Biomedical Engineering Society (BMES)  
 
</p>
<p>Grant Reviewerships: 
• American Heart Association 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>Manuscript Reviewerships: 
• Annals of Biomedical Engineering 
• European Respiratory Journal 
• Respiratory Physiology and Neurobiology 
• Medical Engineering &amp; Physics 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>University Service: 
• Search Committees for Faculty Positions, member  
• Computational Advisory Committee of the Engineering College, member (2004- ) 
• Curriculum Committee of the Engineering College, member (2004-06) 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>PUBLICATIONS 
 
</p>
<p>A) PEER-REVIEWED JOURNALS :   Average Impact Factor (4.7 citations/paper/year) 
 
</p>
<p>A1 Tsoukias, N. M., Z. Tannous, A. F. Wilson and S. C. George. Single Exhalation Profiles of NO and CO2 
in Humans: Effect of Dynamically Changing Flow Rate. Journal of Applied Physiology 85(2):642-652, 
1998. [42 citations] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A2 Tsoukias, N. M. and S. C. George. A Two-Compartment Model of Pulmonary Nitric Oxide Exchange 
Dynamics. Journal of Applied Physiology 85(2):653-666, 1998. [102 citations] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A3 Tsoukias, N. M., A. F. Wilson and S. C. George. Effect of Alveolar Volume and Sequential Filling on 
the Diffusing Capacity of the Lung: I Theory. Respiration Physiology 120(3):231-250, 2000. [11 
citations] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A4 Tsoukias, N. M., D. Dabdub, A. F. Wilson and S. C. George. Effect of Alveolar Volume and Sequential 
Filling on the Diffusing Capacity of the Lung: II Experiment. Respiration Physiology 120(3):251-271, 
2000. [14 citations] </p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p> </p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>iv 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A5 Tsoukias, N. M. and S. C. George. A Single Breath technique with variable flow rate to characterize 
Nitric Oxide Exchange Dynamics in the Lungs. Journal of Applied Physiology 91(1):477-487, 2001. [22 
citations] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A6 Tsoukias, N.M. and S.C. George.  Effect of a Volume Dependent Diffusing Capacity on the Exhalation 
Profile of NO. Annals of Biomedical Engineering 29(9):731-739, 2001. [8 citations] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A7 Tsoukias, N.M. and A.S. Popel.  Erythrocyte consumption of Nitric Oxide in the presence and absence 
of plasma-based Hemoglobin. American Journal of Physiology 282(6):H2265-77, 2002. [17 citations] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A8 Kavdia M., N.M. Tsoukias and A.S. Popel.  A model of Nitric Oxide diffusion in an arteriole: impact of 
hemoglobin based blood substitutes. American Journal of Physiology 282(6):H2245-53, 2002. [18 
citations] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A9 Tsoukias, N.M. and A.S. Popel. A model of nitric oxide capillary exchange. Microcirculation 10(6): 
479-95, 2003. [11 citation] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A10 Tsoukias, N.M., M. Kavdia and A.S. Popel.  A theoretical model of nitric oxide transport in arterioles: 
frequency vs amplitude dependent control of cGMP formation. American Journal of Physiology 
286(3):H1043-56, 2004. [15 citations] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A11 Kapela, A.., Tsoukias N.M. and A. Bezerianos.  New aspects of vulnerability in heterogeneous models 
of ventricular wall and its modulation by loss of cardiac sodium channel function. Medical &amp; Biological 
Engineering &amp; Computing 43(3):387-94, 2005. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A12 Ji, J.W., N.M. Tsoukias, D. Goldman, and A.S. Popel. A computational model of oxygen transport in 
skeletal muscle for sprouting and splitting modes of angiogenesis. Journal of Theoretical Biology 
241(1):94-108, 2006. [1 citations] 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A13 Tsoukias, N. M., D. Goldman, A. Vadapalli, R. N. Pittman and A. S. Popel. A computational model of 
oxygen delivery by hemoglobin-based oxygen carriers in three dimensional microvascular networks 
(submitted), 2006. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>A14 Silva H.S., A. Kapela and N.M. Tsoukias.A mathematical model of plasma membrane electrophysiology 
and calcium dynamics in vascular endothelial cells. (submitted), 2006. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>B) PEER REVIEWED PAPERS IN CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS: 
 
</p>
<p>B1 Tsoukias, N.M., D. Dabdub, A.F. Wilson, and S.C. George. Alveolar volume and Sequential Filling 
Impact the Estimation of DLCO and DLNO.  Proceedings of the First Joint BMES/EMBS Conference. 1999 
IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology 21st Annual Conference and the 1999 Annual Fall Meeting 
of the Biomedical Engineering Society. Piscataway, NJ, USA: IEEE, 1999. p.346 vol.1.  
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>B2  Kapela, A., A. Bezerianos and N.M. Tsoukias. Integrative Mathematical Modeling for Analysis of 
Microcirculatory Function. Biological and Medical Data Analysis. Lecture Notes in Bioinformatics: 
161-171, 2006. 
</p>
<p>B3  Bezerianos A., A. Kapela and N.M. Tsoukias. Theoretical Investigation of Ca2+ Dynamics in 
Normal and Hypertensive Vascular Walls. Computers in Cardiology: 161-171, 2006. 
</p>
<p> </p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p> </p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>v 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C) ABSTRACTS IN CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS: 
 
</p>
<p>C1 Tsoukias, N. M., D. S. Mukai, A. F. Wilson and S. C. George. Flow Rate Dependence of Endogenous 
Nitric Oxide in Humans. AJRCCM 155(4):A558, 1997. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C2 Tsoukias, N. M. and S. C. George. A Two-Compartment Model for the Exchange of Endogenous Nitric 
Oxide in Human Lungs. Annals Biomed. Engineer. 25(1):S10, 1997. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C3 Tsoukias, N. M. and S. C. George. Elimination Rate: A Technique to Identify Alveolar and Airway 
Contributions to Exhaled NO. AJRCCM 157(3):A369, 1998. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C4 Tsoukias, N. M., A. F. Wilson and S. C. George. DLNO as A Function of the Alveolar Volume: Effect on 
Exhaled Nitric Oxide. Annals Biomed. Engineer. 25(1):S10, 1998. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C5 Tsoukias, N. M. and S. C. George. Effect of Production Rates and DL,NO on the Shape of the Nitric 
Oxide Exhalation Profile: A Theoretical Study. FASEB J. 12(4):A499, 1998.  
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C6 Tsoukias, N. M. and S. C. George. Modeling the Effect of Inspiratory Conditions on the Nitric Oxide 
Exhalation Profile. European Respiratory Society, 1998. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C7 Tsoukias, N. M. and S. C. George. A New Method to Measure the Dependence of DLNO and DLCO on 
Alveolar Volume. AJRCCM  159(3):A843, 1999.  
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C8  Tsoukias N.M., and S.C. George. Does endogenous Nitric Oxide approach an equilibrium concentration 
in the alveoli at end-exhalation? AJRCCM 161(3):A000, 2000. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C9 Tsoukias, N.M., and S.C. George. A Single Breath Technique with Variable Flow Rate for the 
measurement of exhaled NO. European Respiratory Society, 2000.  
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C10 Tsoukias N.M., A. Vadapalli, D. Goldman, and A.S. Popel. A computational study of oxygen transport 
in microvascular networks in the presence of Hemoglobin Based Oxygen Carriers. Artificial Cells, 
Blood Substitutes and Immobilization Biotechnology,29(2):173, 2001. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C11 Tsoukias N.M., M. Kavdia, and A.S. Popel. Modeling nitric oxide transport in arterioles in the presence 
of hemoglobin based oxygen carriers. Annals Biomed. Engineer. 29(S1):S58, 2001. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C12 Tsoukias N.M., A. Vadapalli, D. Goldman, and A.S. Popel. A computational study of tissue oxygenation 
by hemoglobin based oxygen carriers. Annals Biomed. Engineer. 29(S1):S73, 2001. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C13 Tsoukias, N.M., M. Kavdia, and A.S. Popel. A theoretical model of nitric oxide transport in arterioles: 
transient versus sustained NO production. FASEB J. 16(5):A853, 2002. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C14 Tsoukias N.M., A. Vadapalli, D. Goldman, and A.S. Popel. A computational study of oxygen delivery 
by hemoglobin-based oxygen carriers from complex microvascular networks. FASEB J. 16(5):A83, 
2002. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C15 Kavdia M., N.M. Tsoukias, A.S. Popel. Effect of hemoglobin-based oxygen carrier on smooth muscle 
nitric oxide availability. FASEB J 16 (5): A853-A853, 2002. 
</p>
<p> </p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p> </p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>vi 
</p>
<p>C16 Kavdia M., N.M. Tsoukias, A.S. Popel. A model of nitric oxide distribution in arterioles in the presence 
of hemoglobin-based blood substitutes. IVth International Symposium on Current Issues in Blood 
Substitutes Research, Stockholm, Sweden, 2002. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C17 Tsoukias N.M. and A.S. Popel. Is there frequency encoded information in EDRF? FASEB J, 2004. 
 
</p>
<p>C18 Isaza D., M. Kanwar and N.M. Tsoukias.  Experimental determination of Nitric Oxide consumption by 
red blood cells. Annals Biomed. Engineer. (in press) 2004. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C19 Isaza D., and N.M. Tsoukias.  Negligible membrane resistance in Nitric Oxide consumption by red blood 
cells. FASEB J (in press), 2005. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C20 M. Kanwar, R. Chawla and N.M. Tsoukias. Simultaneous measurement of NO and Ca2+ concentrations 
in isolated perfused rat mesenteric arterioles. Annals Biomed. Engineer. (in press) 2005. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C21 Kapela A., H. Silva, A. Bezerianos and N.M. Tsoukias.  A mathematical model of integrated NO/Ca2+ 
dynamics in rat mesenteric microvessels. Annals Biomed. Engineer. (in press) 2005. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C22 Kapela A., H. Silva, A. Bezerianos, N.M. Tsoukias.  ‘Mathematical model of endothelium-smooth 
muscle interaction in regulating microcirculatory tone’, FASEB J. 20(4):A283, 2006 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C23 Silva H., A. Kapela, N.M. Tsoukias. ‘A mathematical model of plasma membrane electrophysiology and 
calcium dynamics in rat mesenteric endothelial cells’, FASEB J. 20(4):A410, 2006 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C24 Kapela A. and N.M. Tsoukias.  ‘Conducted vasomotor responses in a multicellular mathematical model 
of a rat mesenteric arteriole. Annals Biomed. Engineer. 2007 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>C25 Nofallah S., R. Ordoñez, J. Hall-Ippolito, and N.M. Tsoukias. Estimation of acetylcholine-induced 
endothelial NO release in vitro using fluorescence microscopy. Annals Biomed. Engineer. 2007 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>D) BOOK CHAPTERS: 
  
</p>
<p>D1 Popel A.S., M. Kavdia, N.M. Tsoukias. Effect of Hemoglobin-based blood substitutes on Nitric Oxide 
transport: Mathematical models.  Keio University International Symposia for Life Sciences and 
Medicine Vol. 12. Artificial Oxygen Carrier: Its Frontline. 2005 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>E) INVITED PRESENTATIONS: 
 
</p>
<p>E1  4th European Symposium on Biomedical Engineering (University of Patras, June 20-25, 2004) 
 
</p>
<p>E2  Department of Chemical &amp; Biomedical Engineering at FAMU-FSU (Tallahassee, November 12, 2004)  
 
</p>
<p>E3  Systems Analysis, Data Mining and Optimization in Biomedicine" (University of Florida, February 2-4, 
2005) 
</p>
<p>E4  3rd Summer School on Emerging Technologies in Biomedicine (University of Patras, July 2-7, 2006) 
 
</p>
<p>E5 Mathematical Biosciences Institute (Ohio State University, January 22-26, 2007) 
 
</p>
<p>E6  2007 Experimental Biology (Washington DC, April 28-30, 2007)  </p>
<p/>
</div>
<div class="page"><p/>
<p> </p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>vii 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>F) THESIS : 
 
</p>
<p>F1  Study of the shrinkage and porosity in air-drying fruits and vegetables. Diploma Thesis. National 
Technical University of Athens, Greece, 1994. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>F2  Characterization of Nitric oxide exchange in human lungs.  Ph.D. Thesis. University of California, 
Irvine, 1999. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>PATENTS : 
 
</p>
<p>P1  George S.C. and N.M. Tsoukias. An apparatus and method for the estimation of flow independent 
parameters which characterize the relevant features of Nitric Oxide production and exchange in the 
human lungs. (WO 01/82782; US 6,866,637) 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>RESEARCH FUNDING: 
 
</p>
<p>RF1  American Heart Association. National Scientist Development Grant (sole PI): Signal transduction in the 
regulation of microcirculatory vascular tone involving Nitric Oxide, 07/01/04-06/30/08. Award amount: 
$260,000. [Top 1.28 percentile]. 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>RF2  Arthur Guyton Award for excellence in integrative physiology, 2006. Award amount: $15,000 
 
</p>
<p>RF3  American Heart Association Florida-Puerto Rico Affiliate. Grand-In-Aid (sole PI): Signal transduction 
in the regulation of microcirculatory vascular tone involving Nitric Oxide, 2004. Award amount: 
$120,000. (Award was declined as alternative to RF1). 
</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p>RF4  Access to Biomedical Engineering. Faculty Research Enhancement Award (sole PI): NO/Ca2+ 
measurements in isolated vessels of the microcirculation, 2004. Award amount: $5,000. </p>
<p/>
</div>
</body></html>